[quirky music]
&l &l
(Dexter)
PREVIOUSLY ON DEXTER...
[thinking]
I CAN HONESTLY SAY I KNOW
WHO MIGUEL PRADO REALLY IS.
MY FIRST GOOD FRIEND.
(Miguel)
WE NEED TO GO AFTER
THE ROOT CAUSE.
BLOOD-SUCKING, SOULLESS
DEFENSE ATTORNEY ELLEN WOLF!
WALK IN THE PARK
TO DISCREDIT YOU, COUNSELOR.
TRY IT.
OH, I'M NOT
THE ONE ON TRIAL.
OH, YOU SHOULD BE.
YOU SHOULD BE!
(Dexter)
THIS IS PERSONAL.
(Miguel)
FUCK YES, THIS IS PERSONAL.
AND IT SHOULD BE
PERSONAL FOR YOU TOO.
AS MY FRIEND.
I'M ASKING YOU
TO DO THIS FOR ME.
SORRY, NO.
WELL, THEN FUCK YOU!
(Harry)
MIGUEL WENT MISSING LAST NIGHT.
ELLEN'S MISSING THIS MORNING.
I HOPE SHE DIDN'T GET
IN AN ACCIDENT OR SOMETHING.
[Dexter thinking]
HE DID IT. MIGUEL REALLY DID IT.
WOW, I DIDN'T
GET IT BEFORE, MIGUEL,
BUT YOU CAN'T BE REASONED WITH,
GUILTED, CONTROLLED.
THIS WHOLE BACK AND FORTH GAME
FOR LEVERAGE IS POINTLESS.
THAT'S RIGHT!
I'LL DO WHAT I WANT WHEN I WANT
TO WHOMEVER I WANT.
COUNT ON IT!
YES, WE WILL MARRY YOU.
(Dexter)
YOU SHOULD BE MY BEST MAN.
WHAT?
I TRUST YOU MORE THAN ANYONE.
(Ramon)
WHY ARE YOU RUNNING YOUR MOUTH
ABOUT FAMILY BUSINESS
TO A GOD DAMN STRANGER?
DEXTER IS NOT
THE PROBLEM HERE.
BETTER KEEP YOUR FUCKING
HANDS OFF OF ME, PENDEJO !
[Dexter thinking]
ELLEN WOLF'S RING.
(Laguerta)
ELLEN WOLF WAS THREATENING
TO WRECK HIS CAREER.
HE HAS A BLACK SUV AND NO ALIBI
FOR THE NIGHT SHE DIED.
YOU THINK MIGUEL HAD SOMETHINGT?
(Laguerta)
I FOUND THIS SAMPLE
IN THE BACK OF HIS CAR.
[Dexter thinking]
WHILE LAGUERTA'S DECIDING,
I'LL BE ELIMINATING
HER PROBLEM.
AND GEORGE KING'S
GOING TO HELP ME.
I'LL COPY HIS M.O.
THEY WON'T EVEN
LOOK FOR ANOTHER SUSPECT.
I AM THIS CLOSE
TO GETTING MY SHIELD,
AND I'M PUTTING IT ALL
AT RISK TO BE WITH YOU!
THEN DEBRA,
WHY ARE YOU?!
I NEED FOR YOU
TO SERIOUSLY THINK ABOUT US.
YOU'VE HAD A BUG UP YOUR ASS
ABOUT DAD FOR MONTHS NOW.
HE DIDN'T CHEAT ON MOM.
BULLSHIT. WHO?
A C.I.
LAURA MOSER. MY MOTHER.
I KINDA NEED A FAVOR.
THAT'S WHAT I'M HERE FOR.
WHAT DO YOU NEED?
ALL THE RECORDS YOU HAVE ON MY
DAD'S CONFIDENTIAL INFORMANTS.
SKINNER. GEORGE KING.
THE NICARAGUAN EMBASSY IS STILL
GIVING ME THE RUNAROUND.
UNTIL WE KNOW
KING'S TRUE IDENTITY,
THERE'S NOT MUCH TO GO ON.
YOU NEED TO HAVE
A LONG CONVERSATION
WITH DEXTER MORGAN.
YOU THINK I'M DONE WITH YOU?
YOU THINK THIS
ENDS HERE?
IT DOESN'T!
IT DOES FOR YOU.
[ethereal guitar music]
&l &l
[Dexter thinking]
THERE ARE FEW MILESTONES IN LIFE
THAT EVOKE A STRONGER RESPONSE
THAN OUR FINAL ACT.
DEATH.
WHAT WAS ONCE MOVING, SPEAKING,
KILLING, AND THREATENING
BECOMES NOTHING
BUT AN EMPTY VESSEL.
WHICH IS NOT SO DIFFERENT
FROM HOW I'VE ALWAYS FELT.
SEVERAL PATCHES OF SKIN
REMOVED FROM THE, UH--
THE SHOULDER AREA.
LIGATURE MARKS
ON THE NECK.
WHY THE FUCK WOULD THE SKINNER
WANNA KILL MIGUEL PRADO?
MIGUEL WAS AFTER FREEBO.
KING HAD TO FIGURE
HE KNEW SOMETHING.
[thinking]
WE ALL REACT
IN DIFFERENT WAYS TO DEATH.
SOME, LIKE RAMON,
CHOOSE ANGER.
OTHERS CLING TO RITUAL.
DEX.
I KNOW HE WAS
YOUR FRIEND.
SO IF YOU WANNA
TAKE A PASS ON THIS...
NAH, THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I GOT IT.
ME, I'LL PLAY
THE GRIEVING FRIEND
WHO BURIES HIMSELF IN HIS WORK.
[melancholy guitar music]
&l &l
YOU CAN TELL A LOT
ABOUT A PERSON
BY THE FRIENDS HE KEEPS.
AND THIS IS MY BEST FRIEND.
GOOD-BYE, MIGUEL.
DON'T FUCKING
TOUCH MY BROTHER.
LET GO OF MY ARM.
NOW.
COME HERE.
I AM GOING TO FIND OUT
WHY THIS HAPPENED.
WE ALL WANT
THE SAME THING, RAMON.
[sighs]
THAT WAS AWKWARD.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER BEEN
ASKED TO LEAVE A FUNERAL BEFORE.
RAMON DIDN'T ASK YOU TO LEAVE,
HE PUSHED YOU OUT THE DOOR.
YEAH, HE WAS DRUNK.
I COULD SMELL
THE FUMES.
HE'S JUST SO ANGRY.
HE'S LOST TWO BROTHERS.
HE DOESN'T KNOW WHO TO BLAME.
WELL, CERTAINLY NOT YOU.
[thinking]
NO, CERTAINLY NOT ME.
HEY.
HOW YOU HANDLING THIS?
OH, YOU KNOW,
A LOTTA DIFFERENT EMOTIONS.
I KNOW MIGUEL WASN'T
THE MAN YOU THOUGHT HE WAS.
BUT YOU LOST A FRIEND.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
BE SO STRONG.
CAN'T HELP IT.
OH, POOR SYL.
SHE HAS SO MUCH
TO DEAL WITH.
I CAN ONLY IMAGINE.
SHE INSISTS WE GO
THROUGH WITH THE WEDDING.
SHE STILL WANTS TO COME
TO THE REHEARSAL DINNER
TOMORROW NIGHT.
WELL...
LIFE GOES ON.
FROM YOUR MOTHER?
SHE STARTED
TEACHING AGAIN
AND CAN'T MISS CLASS.
TOO BAD.
THAT'S MY LOVING MOTHER.
[reading]
"LET'S HOPE THE THIRD
ONE'S THE CHARM."
WHAT'S THAT MEAN?
MMM.
THE KID.
THE THIRD KID
IS THE CHARM.
CODY AND ASTOR ARE CHARMS TOO.
LIKE I SAID,
THAT'S MY LOVING MOTHER.
[thinking]
DID RITA JUST LIE TO ME?
SO HAVE YOU WRITTEN
YOUR VOWS YET?
NOT COMPLETELY.
WHAT SHOULD I SAY?
WELL, YOU CAN TALK
ABOUT TOGETHERNESS,
LOYALTY, ATTRACTION,
HONESTY.
HONESTY. RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, I SHOULD GET HOME
AND KEEP WORKING ON THEM.
MMM. YOU SHOULD
KEEP THAT.
HE GAVE ME SO MUCH.
[thinking]
DARLING RITA,
ONCE YOU WERE
A DREAM AND A PRAYER.
NOW OUR FUTURE
IS AS BRIGHT AS THE SUN
GLINTING OFF
THE MORNING DEW.
AND I VOW THAT I WILL...
[sighs]
SOUNDS LIKE I'M MARRYING
A UNICORN.
[cell phone rings]
[ominous music]
&l &l
(Pratt)
'SCUSE ME, SIR.
YOU THE OCCUPANT?
YEAH.
I'M DETECTIVE PRATT.
PROPERTY MANAGER CALLED US.
THEY FOUND YOUR DOOR OPEN.
YEAH, HE CALLED ME TOO.
WE'RE GONNA NEED YOU
TO TAKE A GOOD LOOK AROUND
AND SEE WHAT'S MISSING.
[chuckles]
IT'S KINDA HARD TO TELL.
(Pratt)
YOUR NEIGHBOR,
A MS. LEVIN,
SAW SOMEONE HANGING
AROUND THE MAILBOXES.
LATIN, KINDA BURLY,
GOATEE.
RING ANY BELLS?
[thinking]
RAMON PRADO.
NO.
THANKS. LET ME KNOW IF
YOU FIND OUT ANYTHING.
YOU GOT IT.
THANK YOU.
(Harry)
MIGUEL WARNED YOU
THAT HIS DEATH
WASN'T GONNA BE
THE END OF THINGS.
SO HIS PLAN WAS TO MAKE ME
HIRE A HOUSEKEEPER?
YOUR SUIT
FOR THE WEDDING.
THAT'S PERSONAL.
RAMON PRADO'S
LIKE A GUT-SHOT ANIMAL.
YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO
WITH A WOUNDED ANIMAL.
YOU PUT IT
OUT OF ITS MISERY.
[exhales]
I CAN'T KILL HIM.
HE DOESN'T MEET THE CODE.
CAN'T KILL HIM.
CAN'T IGNORE HIM.
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF IGNORING HIM.
I CAN USE THE RING TO TIE MIGUEL
TO ELLEN WOLF'S MURDER,
THREATEN TO DESTROY
RAMON'S SAINTED BROTHER'S
REPUTATION FOREVER.
THAT'S ENOUGH
TO GET RAMON TO BACK DOWN.
SARA.
DEXTER?
HOW ARE YOU?
HONESTLY, NOT SO GREAT.
I'M SORRY, IS--IS RAMON IN?
NO.
HE DIDN'T COME HOME
WITH US FROM THE FUNERAL.
DOESN'T ANSWER
HIS CELL.
HE'S BEEN ON A BENDER, DEXTER;
I HAVE NO IDEA WHERE HE IS.
OH.
I'M REALLY WORRIED ABOUT HIM.
IF YOU HEAR FROM HIM,
WILL YOU LET HIM KNOW
I STOPPED BY?
[thinking]
RAMON'S BLOOD FAMILY
DOESN'T KNOW WHERE HE IS.
MAYBE HIS BLUE FAMILY DOES.
[dial tone and dialing]
[line ringing]
[operator on phone]
MORNING. SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT.
YEAH, COULD YOU
PUT ME THROUGH
TO SERGEANT
JESSIE WHITAKER, PLEASE?
ONE MOMENT, PLEASE.
[hold music]
[thinking]
GAIL BRANDON.
FUTURE MOTHER-IN-LAW.
WHILE I'M WAITING, I MAY AS WELL
CHECK INTO MY NEW PARTNER.
(operator)
SERGEANT WHITAKER'S
IN THE FIELD.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO LEAVE A MESSAGE?
UH, THIS IS SORT OF IMPORTANT.
I'M WITH MIAMI METRO HOMICIDE.
YOU THINK YOU CAN
TRACK HIM DOWN?
PLEASE HOLD.
[hold music]
[thinking]
BEFORE SHE LEFT MICHIGAN,
RITA BENNET WOULD HAVE BEEN
RITA...BRANDON.
ACKERMAN.
[thinking]
PAUL BENNET WASN'T
HER FIRST HUSBAND.
SHE WAS MARRIED BEFORE, AT 16.
ENDING IN DIVORCE
SIX MONTHS LATER.
AN IMPETUOUS TEEN MARRIAGE.
WHICH MAKES ME
HER THIRD HUSBAND.
THE CHARM.
THE BRASS IS GIVING US
A BLANK CHECK
AS FAR AS OVERTIME
IS CONCERNED
UNTIL THIS MAN
IS IN CUSTODY.
JORGE OROZCO.
A.K.A. GEORGE KING.
AFFECTIONATELY KNOWN BACK HOME
AS EL FIERRO: THE BLADE.
OROZCO WAS A CAPTAIN
IN THE RESISTENCIA
NICARAGUENSE.
THE CONTRAS.
HE HEADED AN INTERROGATION UNIT.
HE TORTURED PEOPLE
FOR A LIVING.
AND KILLED 'EM.
NOW THIS ALREADY
WAS A BIG CASE.
WITH MIGUEL PRADO'S MURDER,
IT'S OFFICIALLY HUGE.
[hold music playing]
[Whitaker on phone]
THIS IS WHITAKER.
HI, MY NAME IS DEXTER MORGAN.
I'M TRYING TO TRACK DOWN
YOUR OLD PARTNER RAMON PRADO.
WHY?
I'M A FAMILY FRIEND.
SARA TOLD ME HE'S BEEN MISSING
SINCE HIS BROTHER'S FUNERAL.
I FIGURED WITH HIS
PROBLEM AND ALL...
GOTCHA.
ACTUALLY, I HAVEN'T
SEEN HIM SINCE HE LEFT.
I KNOW A FEW PLACES
HE USED TO HANG OUT AT.
I MEAN, BASICALLY ANY BAR
WITHIN A TEN-MILE RADIUS.
(Whitaker)
I CAN GIVE YOU A FEW
OF HIS FAVORITES, IF YOU LIKE.
I'M SURE SARA WOULD
APPRECIATE THAT.
YEAH, I'M SURE.
[thinking]
I'D LOVE TO HELP THEM
WITH GEORGE KING,
BUT I'VE GOT A MORE PRESSING
SITUATION TO DEAL WITH:
MIGUEL'S WOUNDED MESSENGER.
MORGAN...A MINUTE?
SURE, SARGE.
SO IT TOOK A COUPLE OF MONTHS
AND A LOT OF WRANGLING,
BUT MY BUDGET REQUEST
FINALLY CAME THROUGH.
HOMICIDE IS GONNA GET
A LITTLE EXTRA MONEY.
OH, THAT'S GREAT.
MM-HMM.
WE SHOULD GET ONE OF THOSE
CRIME-SIGHT IMAGERS.
HAVE YOU SEEN 'EM?
THEIR PICTURES ARE AMAZING.
REALLY?
I MEAN, THAT'S WHAT
YOU'D SPEND IT ON?
'CAUSE I WAS THINKING
MAYBE WE'D SPEND IT ON
ADDING ANOTHER
DETECTIVE TO OUR SQUAD.
OH.
MAYBE SOMEBODY WHO SAVED
THE LIFE OF A C.I.
WHO ID'D OUR SKINNER.
OHH.
[tearing up]
UH...
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY,
I MEAN, WOW.
THANK YOU.
I PUT IN THE RECOMMENDATION
TO LIEUTENANT LAGUERTA.
SHE'S JUST GOTTA
SIGN THE PAPERWORK.
OH, FUCK.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
WE COULD USE A LITTLE
JOY AROUND HERE.
GOOD WORK.
THANK YOU.
I GOT IT.
I'M GUESSING "IT"
IS SOMETHING GOOD?
MY DETECTIVE SHIELD.
OH, BIG NEWS.
IT'S GIGANTIC NEWS.
ALL LAGUERTA HAS TO DO IS SIGN
THE PAPERS AND I'M GOLDEN.
WELL, I'M SILVER.
WE SHOULD CELEBRATE.
YEAH, COME ON.
I MEAN LATER.
I GOTTA PICK UP THE KIDS,
GO TO THE TAILOR'S...
OH, YEAH, YEAH.
YOU KNOW,
DAD WOULD BE PROUD.
THAT STILL MEANS SOMETHING,
NO MATTER HOW FLAWED HE WAS.
YEAH, LOOK AT US.
YOU'RE GETTING MARRIED.
I'M MAKING DETECTIVE.
THE MORGANS ARE GONNA
BE ALL RIGHT.
I'LL SEE YOU
AT THE REHEARSAL DINNER.
OKAY.
YO, FRANCIS.
ANY PROGRESS
ON MY DAD'S C.I. FILES?
OOH, HE KNEW A LOT OF FOLKS,
I'LL GIVE HIM THAT.
ANYONE OF INTEREST?
I HAVEN'T CULLED
THROUGH EVERYTHING YET.
ARE YOU SURE
YOU WANT ME TO?
SOME THINGS ARE BETTER
LEFT IN A BOX.
I JUST--
I NEED TO PUT A FACE ON HER.
KNOWING ALL THE DETAILS
ISN'T GONNA CHANGE
THE FACT THAT HE WAS
MESSING AROUND ON THE SLY.
I KNOW.
I'LL SEND 'EM UP
AS SOON AS I CAN.
THANK YOU, FRANCIS.
(Laguerta)
DEXTER.
I NEED A WORD.
CITY COUNCIL HAS VOTED
TO NAME THE FREEWAY INTERCHANGE
NEAR MY HOUSE
AFTER MIGUEL PRADO.
I DRIVE THAT WAY
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
HE WAS A HERO.
TO SOME.
HE WAS A COLD-BLOODED
KILLER.
HE MURDERED MY FRIEND,
AND NOW HE'S GOT AN INTERCHANGE?
I'M SORRY.
I'M SORRY--
YOU'RE THE ONLY OTHER PERSON
WHO KNOWS THE TRUTH.
MAYBE IT'S TIME WE LET
OTHERS IN ON THE SECRET.
THERE IS NOTHING TO LINK MIGUEL
TO ELLEN WOLF'S MURDER
EXCEPT EVIDENCE
THAT WAS OBTAINED ILLEGALLY,
AND THEREFORE INADMISSIBLE.
I'LL FIND SOMETHING.
I'LL TEAR HIS LIFE APART
IF I HAVE TO.
HE DOESN'T HAVE
A LIFE ANYMORE.
IT'S HIS FAMILY
YOU'D HAVE TO TEAR APART.
THE COMMUNITY.
THE CUBAN COMMUNITY.
AND YOU STILL MIGHT NOT BE
ABLE TO PROVE ANYTHING.
SO I JUST KEEP IT A SECRET.
I HATE SECRETS.
WE ALL HAVE THEM.
WELL, THEN TELL ME, DEXTER.
HOW AM I SUPPOSED
TO LIVE WITH THIS?
YOU JUST DO.
CAN I GET AN EVERYTHING BURRITO
AND A SIDE OF BEANS,
MAYBE A LITTLE BIT OF--
ANTON.
HEY.
HI.
YOU'RE HERE.
YEAH.
YEAH, I WAS JUST, UM, PICKING UP
SOME THINGS FROM EVIDENCE.
MY WALLET, WATCH,
CHAPSTICK.
I COULD'VE BROUGHT
THAT TO YOU.
OH, IT'S COOL.
IT'S COOL, I GOT IT.
SO HOW YOU DOING?
I'M ALL RIGHT.
GOOD.
OH, BUT--
LOOKS LIKE I'M GONNA
GET MY DETECTIVE SHIELD.
DEBRA, WOW,
THAT'S GREAT.
THANK YOU.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THAT'S GOOD.
YOU WANNA GET SOME CO--
I SHOULD PROBABLY GO.
OKAY.
I'LL SEE YA.
I'LL SEE YOU.
[ominous music]
&l &l
[thinking]
I STOPPED AT FOUR BARS,
GOT A NEW APPRECIATION
FOR HOW MANY ALCOHOLICS
THERE ARE IN MIAMI.
BUT STILL NO RAMON.
MORGAN.
WHAT'S UP?
I JUST FOUND OUT
FROM THE A.D.A.'S OFFICE
THAT THEY'RE
REQUESTING LOGS
FROM THE ANTON BRIGGS
SURVEILLANCE DETAIL.
NOW, I DIDN'T KNOW WHY
UNTIL I READ 'EM.
YOU SLEPT
WITH OUR KEY WITNESS?
THE A.D.A.'S
LOOKING INTO IT?
MIGUEL PRADO WAS.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
THE STATUS OF IT IS NOW.
BUT IT'S A CONFLICT.
AND YOU SHOULD HAVE
GIVEN ME THE HEADS UP.
ESPECIALLY BEFORE I SENT
MY RECOMMENDATION
TO LAGUERTA FOR YOUR SHIELD.
YOU'RE GONNA SPIKE IT NOW?
BUT SHE DESERVES
FULL DISCLOSURE.
DISCLOSURE?
REALLY, SARGE?
DID YOU DISCLOSE
THAT YOU MET GIANNA
BECAUSE YOU WERE OUT
STROLLING FOR A HOOKER?
WHERE DID YOU HEAR THAT?
I--
WHERE'D YOU HEAR THAT?
I KNOW SOMEONE IN VICE.
I'M THE ONLY ONE
THAT KNOWS, I THINK.
IT'S NOT EVEN
THAT BIG OF A DEAL.
FUCK, FUCK!
I AM SORRY. I'M SORRY.
IT'S JUST MY CHICKENS
COMING HOME TO ROOST.
OH, FUCK. FUCK.
I MET DETECTIVE GIANNA
WHILE SEEKING THE COMFORT
OF PROSTITUTES.
'SCUSE ME?
I PROPOSITIONED HER.
SHE REVEALED TO ME
TO BE POLICE.
SHE HAD MERCY ON ME;
SHE LET ME OFF WITH A WARNING.
IT WAS A DARK TIME FOR ME.
I COMPLETELY UNDERSTAND IF YOU
WANNA PURSUE A CASE AGAINST ME.
AS CASES GO,
LAYING YOU OUT
FOR THINKING WITH YOUR DICK
IS PRETTY LOW
ON MY LIST OF PRIORITIES.
ACTUALLY, I WAS LOOKING
FOR SIMPLE HUMAN CONNECTION.
NO. RIGHT.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE ALL HAVE SECRETS WE PREFER
NOT TO SHARE, ANGEL.
SKELETONS.
FEEL FREE TO KEEP
YOURS IN THE CLOSET.
DEEP IN THE CLOSET.
THANKS, MARIA.
MM-HMM.
THERE'S SOMETHING ELSE
YOU SHOULD HEAR FROM ME
INSTEAD OF THE GRAPEVINE.
ANGEL, HOW--HOW DARK
OF A TIME WAS THIS?
IT'S REGARDING MY RECOMMENDATION
OF DEBRA MORGAN FOR DETECTIVE.
[ominous music]
&l &l
(Astor)
SO, WHEN YOU AND MOM
GET MARRIED,
WHAT SHOULD WE CALL YOU?
(Dexter)
UM, I THINK MR. HANDSOME
WOULD BE A GOOD NAME.
[both giggle]
[thinking]
IS THAT YOU, RAMON?
UH, YOU CAN CALL ME
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
I THINK WE'LL JUST
CALL YOU DEXTER.
THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
[thinking]
FOLLOWING ME
WITH KIDS IN MY CAR?
NOW YOU'RE JUST PISSING ME OFF.
MOMENT OF TRUTH.
STOP OR GET A TICKET, ASSHOLE.
[horn honks]
[tires screeching]
DID YOU SEE THAT, DEXTER?
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN DRIVERS DO STUPID THINGS.
LOOKS LIKE HE'S OKAY ENOUGH
TO WALK AWAY.
[thinking]
UNTIL I GET A HOLD OF HIM.
(Rita)
THIS IS GONNA BE A NICE DINNER.
THANK YOU
FOR DOING THIS, DEXTER.
JUST DOING WHAT GROOMS
ARE SUPPOSED TO DO.
SO HOW ARE YOU COMING ALONG
WITH YOUR VOWS?
STILL WORKING ON 'EM.
[thinking]
I'M GOING TO LOB THIS IN
NICE AND EASY.
WHAT KIND OF VOWS DID YOU DO
THE FIRST TIME AROUND?
THE FIRST TIME?
WELL, PAUL AND I JUST RECITED
WHATEVER THE PASTOR SAID.
[thinking]
LIAR, LIAR,
PANTS ON FIRE.
MAITRE D' SAID WE'D BE
SEATED IN 15 MINUTES.
UN-FUCKING-BELIEVABLE.
RAMON, WHY DON'T WE GO OUTSIDE
AND TALK ABOUT THIS.
FUCK YOU.
YOU DON'T TELL ME WHAT TO DO.
(Dexter)
LOOK, THESE PEOPLE HAVE
NOTHING TO DO WITH THIS.
[gun cocks]
I SHOULD PUT A BULLET
IN YOUR HEAD.
IN FRONT OF EVERYBODY.
SO THEY CAN SEE
WHAT IT'S LIKE TO LOSE SOMEONE.
RAMON.
COME ON, YOU NEED
TO PUT THE GUN DOWN
BEFORE ANYONE GETS HURT.
(Debra)
FREEZE, ASSHOLE.
OHH! AAH!
OHH! UHH!
GET YOUR HANDS
OFF OF ME!
I WILL, AS SOON AS I GET
SOME OF YOUR SHERIFF
BUDDIES DOWN HERE!
THANK YOU.
THEY ALL SAY
THE SAME THING.
"KING WAS A VERY
POLITE GARDENER.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
HE'S THE SKINNER."
I HATE POLITE KILLERS.
I HEARD YOU TOOK DOWN
RAMON PRADO LAST NIGHT.
AGAIN.
YEAH, THE PRADOS
MUST LOVE ME.
[phone rings]
MORGAN.
YOU GONNA EAT THAT?
NOT ANYMORE, THANKS.
THAT WAS ROBBERY.
THERE WAS A HIT-AND-RUN
FENDER BENDER
INVOLVING A STOLEN CAR.
TRAFFIC ENFORCEMENT
CAUGHT THE GUY'S FACE.
GUESS WHO.
THEY'RE SENDING
A PHOTO OVER RIGHT NOW.
(Quinn)
GEORGE FUCKING KING.
(Debra)
GOD, THAT'S DEFINITELY HIM.
ROBBERY'S SENDING
THE CAR IN RIGHT NOW.
(Masuka)
I'LL GRAB MY KIT.
WE'LL TEAR THAT CAR APART.
BY THE BOOK,
MR. MORGAN.
IF YOU NEED US,
WE'RE RIGHT OUTSIDE, LIEUTENANT.
THANKS.
HOW'S IT FEEL, RAMON?
HOW THE FUCK DOES WHAT FEEL?
WAKE UP SOBER
FOR THE FIRST TIME IN A WEEK.
LIKE SHIT.
YEAH, THAT SHIT'S
CALLED REALITY.
IT'S GONNA BE LIFE
AS YOU KNOW IT FOR A LONG TIME.
I'M GONNA BE OUTTA HERE
IN A COUPLE OF DAYS.
ONE LAST COUPON FROM YOUR
FAMOUS BROTHER'S REPUTATION.
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
SO YOU DON'T REALLY
HAVE TO BOTHER WITH REALITY.
THAT MUST BE NICE.
YOU KNOW WHAT
MY FUCKING REALITY IS?
MIGUEL TAKES ME ON
AS A BODYGUARD,
AND I ASK HIM WHY.
YOU KNOW WHAT HE SAYS?
TO PROTECT HIM FROM YOU.
DID HE SAY WHY?
NO.
THE ONLY ONE MIGUEL NEEDED
PROTECTION FROM WAS HIMSELF.
THE MAN WAS PARANOID.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
THAT'S TRUE.
YOU KNOW IT AS WELL AS I DO.
LOOK, I SPENT A LOT OF TIME
WITH YOUR BROTHER,
BUT IT WASN'T 24/7;
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HE WAS UP TO
WHEN I WASN'T AROUND.
NEITHER DOES SYL,
NEITHER DO YOU.
WHAT I DO KNOW
IS THIS:
YOU GOT A REALLY UGLY HISTORY.
KIDNAPPING,
BRUTALITY, ABUSE.
YOU TRASHED MY APARTMENT,
YOU FOLLOWED ME.
YOU PUT A GUN IN MY FACE
IN FRONT OF MY FRIENDS,
IN FRONT OF MY PREGNANT
FIANCEE.
WHY, RAMON?
WHAT'S YOUR ENDGAME?
TO HURT YOU.
UNTIL YOU CAME INTO OUR LIFE,
EVERYTHING WAS FINE.
FINE LIKE WHAT?
LIKE OSCAR'S DRUG PROBLEM?
LIKE MIGUEL'S...DARKNESS?
WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT?
WE WERE CLOSE.
MIGUEL AND I.
HE TOLD ME THINGS.
HE TOLD ME HOW HE PUSHED
YOUR FATHER DOWN THE STAIRS
TO PROTECT OSCAR AND YOU.
AND THAT HE ENJOYED IT.
HE FUCKING TOLD YOU THAT?
IT WAS ME THAT DID THAT
TO OUR FATHER.
MIGUEL TOOK IT FROM ME;
MADE IT HIS STORY.
PART OF HIS GOD DAMN LEGEND.
MIGUEL ALWAYS
HAD TO BE THE STAR.
HE GOT THE LOOKS,
THE CHARM,
MAYBE EVEN THE BRAINS,
BUT I GOT THE STRENGTH.
I SPENT MY WHOLE LIFE
TRYING TO HOLD IT TOGETHER,
AND NOW IT'S ALL GONE TO SHIT.
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO.
BULLSHIT.
THOSE CASES
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT,
THE KIDNAPPING,
THE BRUTALITY...
THAT WAS ME SWEEPING UP
AFTER MIGUEL'S FUCK-UPS.
HE WASN'T MAKING
MY PROBLEMS GO AWAY,
I WAS RISKING MY ASS
TO COVER HIS.
I KNOW THE FRUSTRATION,
THE DISAPPOINTMENT,
OF WANTING TO HELP YOUR BROTHER
AND NOT BEING ABLE TO.
WHERE'S YOUR SON RIGHT NOW?
SOCCER PRACTICE.
YOUR DAUGHTER?
PRESCHOOL.
WHERE DO THEY THINK
THEIR FATHER IS?
SARA TOLD THEM SOMETHING.
I--I DON'T KNOW.
SOMEDAY YOUR KIDS
WILL BE OLD ENOUGH
TO SEE THE TRUTH
FOR THEMSELVES.
JUST LIKE YOU DID
WITH YOUR FATHER.
I KNOW.
I'VE BEEN THERE.
THE SINS OF THE FATHER
GO ON AND ON,
FROM KID TO KID TO KID.
UNLESS SOMEONE--YOU--
CHOOSES TO END THEM.
[sighs]
I'VE BEEN THERE TOO.
[thinking]
YOU DON'T ALWAYS HAVE TO DESTROY
A WOUNDED ANIMAL.
SOMETIMES YOU JUST
REMOVE THE THORN.
THOSE DARK LINES...
RETICULATED VEINS.
OH, HOLY SHIT,
IT IS SKIN.
NO, MORE LIKE...
MORE LIKE LEAF.
SO THE ONLY EVIDENCE WE GOT
FROM THE CAR THAT SKINNER STOLE
IS A FRIGGIN' LEAF?
YOU GOTTA BE FUCKING
KIDDING ME.
YUP. TOBACCO LEAF.
TOBACCO?
FUCKIN'-A,
WASN'T THERE A--
KING'S, UH,
FORMER EMPLOYER,
WHAT WAS THE NAME?
THANK YOU, VINCE.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
CIGAR COMPANY.
WHAT WAS IT CALLED?
UH...
EL ROYALE CIGAR COMPANY.
IT'S LISTED
ON THE FIRST TAX FORM
FILLED OUT
BY KING IN 1992.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S GREAT.
THANKS FOR DOING THIS
SO FAST, BRUNO.
HAPPY TO HELP.
NOW, YOU DO THAT.
OKAY.
AND I'LL GET
YOUR SHOES.
ALL RIGHT.
(Harry)
REMEMBER WHAT I TAUGHT YOU.
HOW COULD I FORGET?
MOM'S FUNERAL.
THE RABBIT...
HOPS OVER THE LOG.
YOUR MOTHER WOULD BE SO PROUD.
BOTH OF THEM.
THE RABBIT CRAWLS
UNDER THE LOG.
THE RABBIT RUNS
AROUND THE LOG...
ONE MORE TIME,
BECAUSE HE'S TRYING
TO OUTSMART THE FOX.
THE RABBIT...
DIVES THROUGH
HIS RABBIT HOLE.
SAFE AND SOUND.
(Batista)
WHAT'S THIS?
ALL WE GOT OUT OF SEARCHING
THE CIGAR FACTORY.
TOTAL WASTE
OF TIME.
NO SIGN OF KING?
THE SECURITY GUARD'S THERE
'ROUND THE CLOCK.
NO WAY KING GETS IN OR OUT.
[Cuban guitar music]
&l &l
[thinking]
TOMORROW IS MY WEDDING DAY.
SOME MEN WOULD BE EXCITED.
OTHERS PANICKY.
ME?
I FEEL...CALM.
[grunts]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
HERE ON A SATURDAY?
OH, HEY.
I'M JUST, UH, REANALYZING
SOME OF THE EVIDENCE
FROM KING'S STOLEN CAR.
[ominous music]
&l &l
FRANCIS, YOU CAME THROUGH.
[door opens]
(Laguerta)
MORGAN.
GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
I WANNA TALK TO YOU.
OH, SHIT.
I DIDN'T KNOW SHE WAS HERE.
DID I SAY ANYTHING
BAD ABOUT HER?
YOU'RE NOT THE ONE
SHE'S GONNA REAM.
[knocks]
SIT.
UM...
THAT'S OKAY.
IT SEEMS THE A.D.A.
HAS NOTICED
THAT YOUR PERSONAL
AND PROFESSIONAL LIVES
ARE COLLIDING.
ALL RIGHT.
LISTEN, ANTON WASN'T OFFICIALLY
A C.I. WHEN THAT HAPPENED.
SO IT WAS A ONE-TIME THING?
NO.
STILL GOING ON?
I'M NOT SURE.
DO YOU WANT IT TO?
I DON'T KNOW. HE COULD BE
A KEY WITNESS IN MY CASE.
DOESN'T HAVE
TO BE YOUR CASE.
YOU KNOW WHAT.
YOU GO AHEAD.
YOU TAKE AWAY MY CASE,
YOU TAKE AWAY MY SHIELD.
I DON'T CARE ANYMORE.
BECAUSE IT WASN'T
THE WRONG DECISION.
I WANTED TO BE WITH ANTON.
I STILL WANT TO BE WITH ANTON.
AND THERE IS NO POSSIBLE WAY
THAT US BEING TOGETHER
IS A MISTAKE.
WHICH MEANS YOU'RE NOT
SACRIFICING YOUR
PERSONAL LIFE TO WORK.
GOOD FOR YOU.
CONGRATULATIONS,
DETECTIVE MORGAN.
[scoffs]
WHAT?
YOU'RE ONE OF THE SMARTEST,
HARDEST WORKING,
MOST ANNOYING
PAIN-IN-THE-ASS COPS
IN MY DEPARTMENT.
AND YOU'VE EARNED THIS.
WHAT ABOUT THE A.D.A.'S
ETHICS PROBE?
THE A.D.A. IS DEAD.
TRY ONE OF THESE.
OH!
GANACHE FROSTING.
YOU HOLD ONTO
THAT PERSONAL LIFE.
YEAH.
REMINDS US
WHAT'S IMPORTANT.
CUPCAKES.
[laughs]
ABSO-FUCKING-LUTELY.
[thinking]
SUCH A FAMILIAR SITUATION.
SUCH AN UNFAMILIAR PERSPECTIVE.
[whistling]
[thinking]
GEORGE KING.
SO RAMON WASN'T
THE ONLY ONE FOLLOWING ME.
I UNDERESTIMATED MIGUEL
AFTER ALL.
THIS IS THE PART WHERE MY FEAR
IS SUPPOSED TO BUILD.
I KNOW HIS M.O. BY HEART.
BUT YOU'RE NOT AFRAID.
NO.
I'M NOT.
I AM.
I'VE BEEN SCARED OF IT COMING
TO THIS YOUR WHOLE LIFE.
A VIOLENT END.
I TRIED TO PROTECT YOU.
AND YOU DID.
THIS IS MY FAULT
FOR NOT TRUSTING YOU.
INSTEAD I TRUSTED
MIGUEL FUCKING PRADO.
YOU DID THE BEST
YOU COULD.
I NEED YOU TO UNDERSTAND
SOMETHING, DEXTE
SO DID I.
THE VERY BEST THAT I COULD.
I HOPE TO BE HALF AS GOOD
A FATHER TO MY SON.
YOUR SON.
DAD.
I FORGIVE YOU.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
YOU CRY BEFORE.
THEY'RE NOT
MY TEARS, DEX.
THEY'RE YOURS.
I KNOW, BUT I'VE NEVER...
I'VE NEVER FELT THIS.
YOU'VE NEVER
HAD A SON BEFORE.
YOU WANT TO SEE HIM
COME INTO THE WORLD.
YES.
TO RAISE HIM WITH RITA.
TO WATCH HIM GROW UP.
TO PROTECT HIM.
I KNOW.
I DIDN'T.
UNTIL NOW, WHEN IT'S ALL
GONNA BE TAKEN AWAY.
I WANNA BE THERE FOR HIM.
I'VE NEVER WANTED
ANYTHING SO MUCH IN MY LIFE.
[knocking]
HEY.
HI.
COME IN.
YOU'RE COMPLETELY
DIFFERENT FROM ME.
YOU'RE LAID-BACK,
AND MUSICIAN-Y,
AND...UN-AMBITIOUS.
YOU'RE LIKE VALIUM.
AND YOU'RE LIKE RED BULL.
YOU ARE THE BEST THING
THAT HAS HAPPENED TO ME.
I'M STILL A WITNESS
IN YOUR CASE.
IT'S NOT MY CASE.
I RECUSED MYSELF.
YOU GAVE UP
A CASE--THIS CASE?
I HAD A CHOICE.
I CHOSE YOU.
YOUR TURN.
I'VE ALREADY CHOSEN.
[both laugh]
OKAY.
[cell phone rings]
HOLD ON.
HOLD ON, I'LL TURN IT OFF.
WAIT, JUST, UH--
WHAT?
GEORGE KING WASN'T
AT THAT CIGAR FACTORY.
FUCKING DUH, BUT THAT'S
NOT MY CASE ANYMORE.
WHY?
(Masuka)
WELL, I RE-RAN THE TOBACCO
THAT WE GOT
FROM GEORGE KING'S STOLEN CAR.
IT TURNS OUT IT'S AT LEAST
A DOZEN YEARS OLD.
CALLED THE CIGAR FACTORY.
THEY ONLY MOVED IN
THERE THREE YEARS AGO.
WHERE'D THEY MOVE IT?
[whistling]
[thinking]
I KNOW THAT LOOK.
I'VE HAD THAT LOOK.
HE LIKES CONTROL.
NEEDS IT.
SO I'LL TAKE IT AWAY FROM HIM.
I KILLED FREEBO.
[whistling fades]
SORRY 'BOUT THAT.
I TIED HIM UP.
NOT UNLIKE THIS.
STABBED HIM
IN THE LEFT CAROTID ARTERY.
USED HIS 16-INCH,
CARBON STEEL
BONE SAW TO SEPARATE HIS LIMBS.
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
DIVIDED THEM EQUALLY
AMONGST SIX
BIODEGRADABLE TRASH BAGS.
WHICH ARE LONG GONE NOW,
CARRIED NORTH
ON THE GULF STREAM.
YOU'RE LYING.
USUALLY.
NOT NOW.
NO POINT.
WHY WOULD YOU HAVE
DONE SUCH A THING?
OH, I HAVE MY EXCUSES
AND JUSTIFICATIONS,
BUT, REALLY, I JUST...
NEED TO.
LIKE YOU.
YOU HAVE YOUR FLIMSY EXCUSES:
FINDING FREEBO,
GETTING YOUR MONEY.
BUT YOU KNOW HE'S DEAD.
YOU KNOW THERE'S NO MONEY.
SO REALLY, YOU'RE JUST...
A KILLER.
A MONSTER.
THE STUFF OF NIGHTMARES.
I COULD KILL YOU NOW.
IF YOU CAN CONVINCE
YOURSELF I'M LYING.
THAT YOU NEED TO SKIN ME
TO GET INFORMATION OUT OF ME.
YOU ARE LYING.
YOU DO KNOW
WHERE HE IS.
MIGUEL PRADO
TELL YOU THAT?
HE WANTED ME DEAD.
SO HE USED YOU.
HE PLAYED
ON YOUR OBSESSION.
IT PROBABLY
WASN'T TOO HARD.
I MEAN, YOU'RE A LITTLE
SINGLE-MINDED.
[bangs table]
LET'S HOPE
YOU'RE THIS TALKATIVE
ONCE I GET MY TOOLS.
[creak]
[thinking]
A WOLF WOULD CHEW OFF
ITS OWN PAW.
ITS SURVIVAL INSTINCT
IS THAT FIERCE.
SO IS MINE.
[bone cracking]
AAH!
AHH.
[grunts]
AAH!
[struggling]
[police siren]
GAH! AHH!
[neck cracks]
[grunting]
FUCK!
KING'S TRUCK, 11:00.
SHIT!
[grunting]
(officer)
NO WAY I COULD STOP
IN TIME, MA'AM.
HE FUCKIN'
CAME OUT OF NOWHERE.
[police radio chatter]
JESUS, OFFICER.
HE SCRAPED
HIS FUCKING SKIN OFF.
YEAH, WELL, WHAT GOES AROUND
COMES AROUND.
AND IT'S DETECTIVE.
[pleasant guitar music]
&l &l
DEXTER'S HERE.
HE JUST PULLED UP.
OH, FINALLY.
NOTHING TO BE CONCERNED ABOUT,
BUT HE KIND OF HAD
A LITTLE ACCIDENT.
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE TOOK A TUMBLE
DOWN SOME STAIRS.
BROKE HIS HAND.
OH, MY GOD.
RITA, HE'S FINE.
HE CAN'T WAIT
TO GET MARRIED.
HI.
DEXTER!
DEXTER, YOUR ROOM
IS DOWN THE HALL.
YOU CANNOT BE IN HERE.
WOW. YOU LOOK...
WOW.
YOU CAN'T SEE HER
'TIL THE WEDDING.
IT'S BAD LUCK.
I THINK I GOT
THAT ONE COVERED, SWEETIE.
OH, BABY, ARE YOU OKAY?
JUST EMBARRASSED,
MORE THAN ANYTHING.
(Syl)
SWEETHEART, WHY DON'T WE GO
AND DO YOUR MAKEUP?
I'M SORRY.
IT'S OKAY.
YOU'RE NOT ANGRY?
WHY WOULD I BE?
IT'S NOT LIKE YOU BROKE
YOUR HAND ON PURPOSE.
I'M JUST GLAD
YOU'RE HERE.
SAFE.
ME TOO.
ALL RIGHT,
NOW GO, GO.
OKAY.
BE READY IN A JIFFY.
YOU REALLY DO LOOK BEAUTIFUL.
[thinking]
SHE WANTS TO HOLD
ONTO HER SECRET.
AND I'M GOING TO RESPECT THAT.
IT SEEMS ONLY FAIR,
GIVEN THE SECRETS
I KEEP FROM HER.
WE ALL HAVE SECRETS.
IN THAT WAY,
I'M JUST LIKE EVERYONE ELSE.
SORTA.
(Debra)
HEARD ABOUT YOUR LITTLE FALL.
ARE YOU OKAY?
YEAH, I'M FINE.
I HEARD YOU NABBED
GEORGE KING?
YEAH.
GREAT, BIG, SCARY
CONTRA BOOGEYMAN
GETS SURROUNDED AND TAKES
THE CHICKEN-SHIT WAY OUT.
DEATH BY COP.
I'M GLAD HE'S THE ONLY ONE
WHO GOT HURT.
YEAH, ME TOO.
YUCK.
ME IN A DRESS.
I FEEL LIKE A TRANSVESTITE.
[both laugh]
COME HERE.
RABBIT GOES
UNDER THE LOG...
HOPS OVER THE LOG...
AGAIN...
THEN...
THROUGH HIS HOLE.
SAFE AND SOUND.
THANKS.
JUST REMEMBER,
CODY HAS YOUR RINGS.
AND DON'T LOCK YOUR KNEES WHEN
YOU'RE STANDING UP UP THERE.
YOU'LL DROP
LIKE A GOD DAMN STONE.
WHERE ARE YOUR VOWS?
RIGHT HERE.
I'M SO HAPPY FOR YOU.
JUST WISH DAD
COULD BE HERE.
I HAVE A FEELING HE IS.
ENOUGH OF THIS
SAPPY SHIT.
LET'S GET YOU
FUCKIN' HITCHED.
I HONOR YOU.
I LOVE YOU.
I MARRY YOU.
I PROMISE...
TO BE THE VERY BEST HUSBAND
AND FATHER
THAT I CAN BE.
[thinking]
A COMPLETELY,
UTTERLY HONEST VOW.
[applause]
[slow Cuban guitar music]
&l &l
(Dexter)
DEXTER MORGAN: FAMILY MAN.
ALL MY PREVIOUS ATTEMPTS
AT HUMAN CONNECTION
HAVE ENDED IN...
WELL, DEATH.
AND NOW I HAVE
A PARTNER FOR LIFE.
HOW DID THAT HAPPEN?
AM I DRAWN TO THE SAFETY
OF BELONGING,
OR BEING PART OF SOMETHING
BIGGER THAN ME?
EITHER WAY,
I'M A MARRIED MAN.
SOON TO BE A FATHER.
BUT WHAT DO I HAVE
TO OFFER A CHILD?
JUST...ME.
DEMENTED DADDY DEXTER.
MAYBE I'M MAKING
THE BIGGEST MISTAKE OF MY LIFE.
BUT WHO'S PERFECT?
CERTAINLY NOT ME.
CERTAINLY NOT HARRY.B
SURE, I'M STILL WHO I WAS,
WHO I AM.
QUESTION IS,
WHAT DO I BECOME?
THERE ARE SO MANY BLANKS
LEFT TO FILL IN.
BUT RIGHT NOW, AT THIS MOMENT,
I'M CONTENT.
MAYBE EVEN...
HAPPY.
AND I HAVE TO ADMIT,
WHEN ALL IS SAID AND DONE...
LIFE IS GOOD.
Captioning by CaptionMax
www.captionmax.com